(打雷)
[THUNDER CRASHES]
(雨倒)
[RAIN POURS]
[记者1]:飓风维拉
[REPORTER 1]: Hurricane Vera
目前为四级风暴，正在加强。
currently a Category Four storm and strengthening.
预计会有很多损失，尤其是来自大风的损失
A lot of damage is expected, especially from the winds--
[2]记者:……宣布审判吗
[REPORTER 2]: ...is announcing that the trial
对抗Los Urabenos贩毒集团
against Los Urabenos drug cartel
由于天气原因推迟了——
has been postponed due to the weather--
[记者3]:针对哥伦比亚贩毒集团的案件
[REPORTER 3]:The case against the Colombian drug cartel
可能是维拉飓风的第一个受害者。
may be Hurricane Vera's first casualty.
法院，市政府官员，都被遣送回家了
Courts, city officials, all being sent home--
[记者4]:请听
[REPORTER 4]: Please follow
紧急疏散指令。
emergency evacuation instructions.
如果不能躲在——
If unable to shelter in--
[记者5]:行动迅速，而且有预期
[REPORTER 5]: Moving fast and expected to be
一小时后就会穿过华盛顿市区。
through the D.C. Metropolitan area in the next hour.
[记者6]:不要被晴朗的天空所愚弄
[REPORTER 6]: Don't be fooled by clear sky--
[记者7]:飓风维拉，目前是四级风暴
[REPORTER 7]: Hurricane Vera, currently a Category Four storm
和加强。
and strengthening.
预计会有灾难性的风灾。
Catastrophic wind damage is expected.
强制疏散已经生效
Mandatory evacuations have been in effect
但这扇窗已经关闭了
but that window is already closing
因为风暴即将登陆
as the storm is about to make landfall
外层带已经在这里了
and the outer bands are already here
让人想起桑迪飓风
reminding so many of Hurricane Sandy
几年前。
a few years back.
华盛顿和弗吉尼亚地区正处于攻击目标之中。
The D.C. and Virginia area directly in the crosshairs.
(男子用西班牙语大喊)
[MAN SHOUTS IN SPANISH]
让我们把这只鸟绑起来。
[AGENT]: Let's tie this bird down.
他们要关闭机场。
They're shutting down the airport.
走吧，走吧，走吧。
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
快车,快车,快车。
Rapido, rapido, rapido.
每个人都在。
Everybody in.
(打雷)
[THUNDER CRASHES]
(雨倒)
[RAIN POURS]
[记者]:现在的情况非常危险。
[REPORTER]: A very dangerous situation right now.
如果你看我身后
If you look behind me
你可以看到我们现在看到的
you can see what we're seeing now
街头几乎空无一人。
streets practically empty.
所有应该撤离的人都撤离了
Everyone who was supposed to evacuate has done so
在大多数情况下。
for the most part.
(敲门)
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
我们要面对的是四级强地震
We're looking at a strong Category Four
在登陆,所以……
at landfall, so...
我们能过一遍吗?
[WOMAN]: Can we go over this?
[记者]:现在的情况非常危险。
[REPORTER]: A very dangerous situation right now.
我只是想确认我们得到的信息是正确的
I just wanna make sure we have the correct info
你的见证。
for your testimony.
(雷声隆隆地)
[THUNDER RUMBLES]
好的。
OK.
(打雷)
[THUNDER CRASHES]
你和贩毒集团的合作是五年前开始的吗?
Your work with the cartels started five years ago?
六。
Six.
我们的线人告诉我们他们最近转移了资金
So, our sources tell us that they recently moved their money
cryptocurrency。
into a cryptocurrency.
你知道这事吗?
Do you know anything about that?
和航班吗?
And the flight?
他们降落。他们很好。
They landed. They're fine.
他们刚好在暴风雨来临前到达。
They got in just before the storm.
他们应该很快就到。
They should be here soon.
它们是我的全部家当。
They're all I have.
阿米莉亚和她父亲。你明白吗?
Amelia and her father. You understand?
我得确保他们是安全的。
I need to know that they will be safe.
我将作证……
I will testify...
但我要上报纸。
but I want it in the papers.
答应我
Promise me
我们会在美国受到保护
that we will be protected here in the US
不是在哥伦比亚。
not in Colombia.
我们不能再回去了。这不是安全的。
We can't go back there. It's not safe.
你不知道他们对我的家人做了什么。
You don't know what they've done to my family there.
答应我。
Promise me.
是的。
Yes.
这在证人保护协议里。
It's in the witness protection agreement.
你没什么好担心的。我向你保证。
You have nothing to worry about. I promise you.
(雷声隆隆地)
[THUNDER RUMBLES]
[代理人]:现在不远了。
[AGENT]: Not too far now.
再走几英里，我们就到安全屋了。
A few more miles, we'll be at the safe house.
(轮胎发出尖锐的声音)
[TIRES SCREECH]
好的，我知道了。
[MAN]: OK, got 'em.
正在向南执行任务。
Heading south on Mission.
(他说西班牙语)好吗?
[HE SPEAKS SPANISH] OK?
(他会说西班牙语)
[HE SPEAKS SPANISH]
(大声崩溃)
[LOUD CRASH]
(金属擦伤)
[METAL SCRAPES]
[雷声轰鸣]-[女孩呻吟]
[THUNDER CRASHES] - [GIRL GROANS]
[特工1呻吟]-[女孩呻吟]
[AGENT 1 GROANS] - [GIRL GROANS]
(代理2咕哝)
[AGENT 2 GRUNTS]
你们对吧?-后面的人都没事吧?
You guys alright? - Everybody alright in the back?
啊哈。-我很好。
Uh-huh. - I'm good.
(他咕哝声)
[HE GRUNTS]
(他叹了口气)
[HE SIGHS]
(他咕哝声)
[HE GRUNTS]
[枪声]-[女孩尖叫]
[GUNSHOTS] - [GIRL SCREAMS]
[特工2叫喊]-[枪声]
[AGENT 2 YELLS] - [GUNFIRE]
(女裤)-我中弹了。
[GIRL PANTS] - I'm hit.
(枪声)-有多严重?
[GUNSHOTS] - How bad?
(枪声)
[GUNSHOTS]
(他咕哝声)
[HE GRUNTS]
别为我担心。
Don't worry about me.
保护方案。
Protect the package.
(玻璃仰卧起坐)
[GLASS CRUNCHES]
(枪声)
[GUNSHOTS]
[代理3]:把你的手给我。——(女孩咕哝声)
[AGENT 3]: Give me your hand. - [GIRL GRUNTS]
(人咕哝声)
[MAN GRUNTS]
(他咕哝声)
[HE GRUNTS]
(枪声)
[GUNSHOTS]
(他呻吟)
[HE GROANS]
(枪声)
[GUNSHOTS]
[GUNFIRE]
(枪声)
[GUNSHOTS]
住下来!
Stay down!
走吧!
Go!
(他的裤子)
[HE PANTS]
[枪声]-[他呻吟]
[GUNSHOT] - [HE GROANS]
得到低!保持低!上车，上车，上车!
Get low! Stay low! Get in, get in, get in!
(男人的裤子)
[MAN PANTS]
[他低语]:冷静。保持冷静。
[HE WHISPERS]: Calm. Stay calm.
(男):你在找什么?
[MAN]: What are you looking for?
我以为我们打中他们了。他们就在这附近的某个地方。
I thought we hit them. They're around here somewhere.
他们不是在这里。
They're not here.
我们走吧，伙计!
Let's get out of here, man!
阿姆斯特朗探员，收到了吗?
Agent Armstrong, you copy?
我是贝内特探员。
This is Agent Bennett.
(对讲机中):收到了吗?——(无线静态)
[ON RADIO]: Do you copy? - [RADIO STATIC]
(无线电颤音)-我是阿姆斯特朗。
[RADIO TRILLS] - This is Armstrong.
你的情况如何，贝内特探员?
What's your status, Agent Bennett?
班纳特:我们找到了那个女孩和她爸爸。
[BENNETT]: We have the girl and her dad.
我们征用了一个[模糊的]。
We've commandeered an [INDISTINCT].
前往……
Headed to...
去中富集合点。
to rendezvous point Nakatomi.
西哈默尔。
West on Hamel.
埃塔十分钟。
ETA ten minutes.
如果他们来了，你就呆在这儿!
You stay here, if they come!
你要去哪里?-(他用西班牙语大喊)
Where are you going? - [HE SHOUTS IN SPANISH]
疏散命令已经发出——
[RADIO PRESENTER]: Evacuation orders have gone out--
(女人叹了口气)
[WOMAN SIGHS]
是的，不，我知道我要求的是一大笔钱
Yes, no, I know it's a lot of money I'm asking for
但你知道我有能力的。
but you know I'm good for it.
来吧,不
Come on, Don
你一直在为我们偿还贷款，自从我爸爸
you've been servicing our loan since my dad--
是的。
Yes.
是的，不，我知道我的信用评级现在不是很好
Yes, no, I know my credit rating is not great right now
但你知道这是离婚造成的。
but you know it was the divorce that caused that.
我问你一件事。
Let me ask you one thing.
你能不能。-[电话响了]
Would you even consi-- - [PHONE CLICKS]
喂?
Hello?
[雷声轰鸣]-[远处的警报响起]
[THUNDER CRASHES] - [DISTANT ALARM BLARES]
(报警变得响亮)
[ALARM GROWS LOUDER]
(警报突然响了)
[ALARM BLARES]
琳达!
Linda!
泰勒，你去哪儿了?
Taylor, where have you been?
他们吓坏了。——(键盘哔哔声)
They're freaking out. - [KEYPAD BEEPS]
谁打开了火警警报?——(报警停止)
Who turned the fire alarm on? - [ALARM STOPS]
你觉得呢?
Who do you think?
火灾报警器不仅仅是为火灾紧急情况而设的。
Fire alarms are not for fire emergencies only.
他们可以在任何紧急情况下使用
They can be used in case of any emergency
通知适当的——
to notify the proper--
好的。好了，亚瑟，我们知道了。
OK. OK, Arthur, we got it.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
郡里的货车有消息吗?
Any word on the county van?
不能达到他们。
Can't reach 'em.
你在开玩笑吧。
You're kidding.
他们一小时前就该来查看我们的接机情况了。
They're supposed to check on our pick-up an hour ago.
手机。——啊!废话!
Phones are down. - Ugh! Crap!
他们迟到了。他们在哪儿?
They're late. Where are they?
我们得让所有人离开这里。
We've got to get everyone out of here.
你能试试固定电话吗?
Can you try the landline?
我试着它。这是也。- [TAYLOR]:座机?
I tried it. It's out too. - [TAYLOR]: The landline?
不是因为风暴。
Well, not because of the storm.
(叹了口气)
[SHE SIGHS]
真不敢相信他们在紧急情况下就把我们关了。
I can't believe they shut us off in an emergency.
这是一场可怕的飓风。
It's a freaking hurricane.
(泰勒叹了口气)
[TAYLOR SIGHS]
我猜和唐的通话不顺利吧?
I take it the call with Don didn't go well?
我想终于到了。
I think this is finally it.
来吧，别这么轻易就放弃。
Come on, don't give up so easy.
你答应他。
You promised him.
我爸爸是个梦想家，好吗?
Well, my dad was a big dreamer, OK?
我是一个现实主义者。
I'm a realist.
我救不了所有人。
I can't save everybody.
我已经尽力了。
You know, I did everything I could.
就是这里了，琳达。
This is it, Linda.
每个人都在哪里?
Where is everyone?
我在这里!
I'm here!
(雷声裂缝)
[THUNDER CRACKS]
玫瑰吗?
Rose?
艾达?
Ida?
(叹了口气)
[SHE SIGHS]
任何…货车上有什么发现吗?
Any... Anything on the vans yet?
线路还是死线。我们该怎么办?
Lines are still dead. What are we gonna do?
(叹了口气)
[SHE SIGHS]
(遥远的聊天)
[DISTANT CHATTER]
维拉飓风，目前是四级风暴
Again, Hurricane Vera, currently a Category Four storm and--
哦，Fonzy又在做饭了吗?
[MAN]: Oh, is Fonzy cooking again?
我不会就这么站在这里听这家伙说话。
I'm not gonna just stand here and listen to this guy.
你以为你是谁，对我们呼来喝去的?
Who do you think you are, bossing us around?
他是一个上校。
He's a colonel.
中校。
Lieutenant Colonel.
是的,对的。
Yeah, right.
“上校”，加上引号。
"Colonel", with air quotes.
看到了吗?空气引号。
See? Air quotes.
(泰勒):嗨。嘿。这是怎么回事?
[TAYLOR]: Hey. Hey. What's going on in here?
为什么食物都出来了，福兹?——我饿了。
And why is the food out, Fonzy? - I'm hungry.
你是个吃货。
You're a stress eater.
是啊，别以为我们不知道
Yeah, and don't think we don't know
你一直在房间里做饭。
you've been cooking in your room.
是的。所以呢?
Yeah. So?
你也有愤怒的问题。
You have anger issues, too.
是的,但是……
Yeah, but...
(他叹了口气)我正在努力。
[HE SIGHS] I'm working on it.
你得告诉这个叫T的家伙
You gotta tell this guy, T
有辆货车来接我们。
we got a van coming to pick us up.
他说我们得待在这里避难。
He says we have to stay here and shelter.
是啊，掩体就位。
Yeah, shelter in place.
不是我的问题，是新闻。
And it's not me, it's the news.
反正出去也太危险了。
It's too dangerous to go out there anyway.
听着，如果你有意见的话
Look, if you have a problem with it
你可以去找当局。
you can take it up with the authorities.
你想让我们留在这里被炸成碎片吗?
You want us to stay here and get blown to smithereens?
你告诉他，T。
You tell him, T.
事实上，每个人
Well, the truth is, everyone
我不确定疏散车来了。
I'm not sure the evacuation van's coming.
哦,上帝。——(重叠的声音)
Oh, good Lord. - [OVERLAPPING VOICES]
坚持住!等等,每一个人。等一等。
Hold on! Hold on, everyone. Hold on.
你确定你听说的避难所就是这个吗?
Are you sure that's what you heard about shelter in place?
没错，警长莱特迈尔开了个新闻发布会
Yeah, Sheriff Rightmire held a press conference
说县里所有尚未撤离的人
said everyone in the county who hasn't already evacuated
就是在原地躲雨。
is to shelter in place.
我们不能离开。
We're not to leave.
大家都听说过吗?
Is that what everyone heard?
我听到它。
I heard it.
我也听到了。
I heard it, too.
好的。好吧。
OK. Alright.
好吧，这就是避难所。——(ARTHUR):哦。
Well, shelter in place it is. - [ARTHUR]: Oh.
现在让大家都回自己的房间，好吗?
Let's get everyone back to their rooms for now, OK?
我觉得她看起来不太好。
Mm. She don't look good to me.
累了。
Tired.
我去把蜡烛拿出来，以防停电。
I'll get the candles out in case the power goes out.
它会浪漫。呃,罗西?
It'll be romantic. Eh, Rosie?
你把蜡烛留给自己吧。
You keep your candles to yourself.
[男人笑]-[罗丝]:嗯。
[MEN CHUCKLE] - [ROSE]: Mm.
[男人咕哝着]-[特工裤子]
[MAN GRUNTS] - [AGENT PANTS]
保持下来。
Stay down.
(打雷)
[THUNDER CRASHES]
让我看一下。
Let me take a look at that.
你得把它压住。抓住。
You need to put pressure on that. Hold tight.
我们要离开。我们走吧。
We gotta leave. Let's go.
(男人呻吟)
[MAN GROANS]
保持低。保持低。
Keep low. Keep low.
(雷声隆隆地)
[THUNDER RUMBLES]
嗯…请回您的房间。
Uh... Back to your room, please.
得了吧，T。
Oh, come on, T.
谢谢你！-泰勒(笑)
Thank you. - [TAYLOR CHUCKLES]
你们所有人，就现在，请…
All of you, just for now, please...
(雨倒)
[RAIN POURS]
噢!
Ooh!
摆动。
Wiggle it.
这有个窍门。
There's a trick to it.
(泰勒呻吟)哦，我总是忘记这一点。
[TAYLOR GROANS] Oh, I always forget that.
(她咕哝声)
[SHE GRUNTS]
好的。
OK.
(IDA嗡嗡)
[IDA HUMS]
你怎么能一直这么冷静?
How do you always stay so calm in all of this?
(她笑)
[SHE CHUCKLES]
我经历过几次风暴。
I've been through a few storms before.
它会很好的。——(打雷)
It'll be alright. - [THUNDER CRASHES]
好吧……——(她嗡嗡)
Alright... - [SHE HUMS]
如果停电了，显示器有备用电池
If the power goes out, the monitor has a backup battery
这样就……
and that'll...
这会起作用的，好吗?所以，就让它开着吧。
That'll kick in, OK? So, just leave that on.
没有那东西我怎么活了93年?
How did I live 93 years without that thing?
(他们轻声地笑起来)
[THEY CHUCKLE]
这不是让我心跳的原因，亲爱的。
That's not what's keeping my heart going, honey.
是的,嗯…——(她笑)
Yeah, well... - [SHE CHUCKLES]
我知道现在很艰难。
I know it's hard times here right now.
(她会说西班牙语)
[SHE SPEAKS SPANISH]
不要担心你的生活，你要吃什么或喝什么。
Don't worry about your life, what you will eat or drink.
看天上的鸟。
Look at the birds of the air.
他们不播种也不收获
They neither sow nor reap
然而，你的天父养活了他们。
and yet, your heavenly Father feeds them.
别担心。
Don't worry.
他会提供。
He'll provide.
(打雷)
[THUNDER CRASHES]
我希望我能相信。
I wish I could believe that.
(她轻笑)你会的。就像你父亲一样。
[SHE CHUCKLES] You will. Just like your father.
需要我扶你回到床上吗?
Do you want me to help you get back into bed?
不。我很好。
No. I'm fine.
(泰勒叹了口气)
[TAYLOR SIGHS]
[隆隆雷声]-[倾盆大雨]
[LOUD THUNDER RUMBLES] - [HEAVY RAIN POURS]
(雷声裂缝)
[THUNDER CRACKS]
(她嗅探)
[SHE SNIFFS]
(叹了口气)
[SHE SIGHS]
(旋钮当啷声)
[KNOB CLANKS]
(雷声隆隆地)
[THUNDER RUMBLES]
不。不,谢谢。
No. No, thanks.
[FONZY嗡嗡]
[FONZY HUMS]
女士们……
Ladies...
不。去坐下。
No. Go sit down.
(遥远的风的咆哮)
[DISTANT WIND HOWLS]
(泰勒哼了一声)-哦，让我来帮你。
[TAYLOR GRUNTS] - Oh, let me help you with that.
对不起。
Sorry.
他们想在一起。很难拒绝。
They wanted to be together. It's hard to say no.
尽管严格来说，泰勒是对的。
Although, technically, Taylor's right.
联邦应急管理局建议人们呆在室内
FEMA recommends staying in interior rooms
在这种情况下。
in situations like this.
无论如何,书呆子。
Whatever, nerd.
我只是说，如果我们都被埋在废墟里可别怪我。
I'm just saying, don't blame me if we all get buried in debris.
哦,亚瑟!
Oh, Arthur!
把它们都拿走。
Just take them all.
让我们从痛苦中解脱出来。
Put us all out of our misery.
哦,不。今天是星期二。
Oh, no. Today's Tuesday only.
相信我，你不会想把星期二和星期三连在一起的。
You do not want to combine Tuesday and Wednesday, trust me.
混合的日子等于紫色的雾霾。
Mixing days equals purple haze.
好吧。好了，孩子们，够了。
Alright. Alright, kids, that's enough.
我们可以待在这里。对吧?不过只是暂时的。
We can stay in here. Alright? Just for now though.
她做的怎么样?-我们还在坚持
How's she doing? - We're hanging in there.
(敲门)
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
(雷声裂缝)
[THUNDER CRACKS]
DEA。
DEA.
我们能进来吗?需要帮助。
Can we come in, please? Need help.
进来吧，亲爱的。
[TAYLOR]: Come on in, sweetie.
班纳特科尔,DEA。
Cole Bennett, DEA.
你好，我是泰勒·沃德。我是这里的老板。
Hi, I'm Taylor Ward. I'm the owner of this place.
发生了什么事?他是伤害吗?
What happened? Is he hurt?
这里是医疗机构吗?
Is this is a medical facility?
辅助生活。-[琳达]:怎么了?
Assisted living. - [LINDA]: What's going on?
琳达，你能给他们拿几条毛巾吗?
[TAYLOR]: Linda, can you please grab them some towels?
你们这里有医生吗?-我是护士。没有医生,没有。
Do you have a doctor here? - I'm a nurse. No doctor, no.
发生了什么事?-我们撞车了。
What happened? - We've been in a collision.
这些人是由我保护的
These people are under my protection
作为联邦审判的可能证人。
as possible witnesses in a federal trial.
8个街区外有个联邦应急管理局的指挥所。
There's a FEMA command post about eight blocks away.
电话没电了。
The phones are dead.
我得步行过去。
I've gotta make it there on foot.
我可以把它们交给你保管吗?
Can I leave them in your care?
女士吗?-是的。当然,是的。是的。
Ma'am? - Yeah. Of course, yes. Yes.
泰勒，怎么了?
Taylor, what's going on?
能帮我准备一下203房吗?我们把它们放在这里。
Can you prep room 203, please? We'll put them up there.
你会没事的。
[COLE]: You'll be OK.
我说过了，我们是养老院的。我不是…
Like I said, we're assisted living. I'm not...
我不确定我能帮上什么忙，但我会尽我所能。
I'm not sure I can help but I'll do whatever I can.
很感激。你在这儿会没事的。
Appreciate it. You'll be alright here.
照顾好你的父亲。
Take care of your father.
(他叹了口气)谢谢。
[HE SIGHS] Thank you.
(泰勒叹了口气)
[TAYLOR SIGHS]
快进来吧。
Just come right in here.
好了。(她咕哝声)
There we go. [SHE GRUNTS]
好吧……
Alright...
让我们来……——(男人的裤子)
Let's take a... - [MAN PANTS]
如果我能帮到你，我得去看看。
I need to take a look if I'm gonna be able to help you.
发生了什么事?
What happened?
帕索?
Que paso?
Hablar单身吗?
Hablar Inglés?
是的。
Yes.
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
他是旧金山。
He is Francisco.
我是阿米莉亚。
I am Amelia.
泰勒。
Taylor.
让我看看。
Let me take a look.
(叹了口气)
[SHE SIGHS]
好的。
OK.
…到处都是碎片。
...we have debris flying everywhere.
我们有一个轮毂盖。我绝对推荐……
We have a hubcap. I would definitely recommend...
(门咯吱声)
[DOOR CREAKS]
(她喘息声)
[SHE GASPS]
[她呜咽喘息]
[SHE WHIMPERS AND GASPS]
(她窒息)
[SHE CHOKES]
(窒息停止)
[CHOKING STOPS]
(雷声裂缝)
[THUNDER CRACKS]
这是枪伤。
This is a bullet wound.
我还没准备好在这里处理这事?
I'm not equipped to take this out here, OK?
我会尽我所能把它打扮得漂漂亮亮
I'm gonna dress it as best as I can
直到我送你去医院
until I can get you to a hospital.
你接通911了吗?-不，是暴风雨…
Did you get through with 911? - No, the storm, it's...
我需要纱布和其他用品。
I need gauze and supplies.
纱布用完了。
We're out of gauze.
你别拿我开玩笑了。
You're kidding me.
好了，这里，压紧点。
Alright, here, put some pressure on that.
我们去看看，好吗?
Let's go take a look, alright?
来吧。
Come on.
(他说西班牙语)他沿着这条路走。
[HE SPEAKS SPANISH] He went up the road.
从你的妈妈。
From your mama.
把它。
Take it.
保持……
Keep it...
总是这样。——(她抽泣)
always. - [SHE SOBS]
不…
No...
(他叹了口气)
[HE SIGHS]
(他说西班牙语)小麻雀。
[HE SPEAKS SPANISH] Little sparrow.
别担心。一切都会好的。
Don't worry. It will be alright.
保留它。
Keep it.
是很重要的。
Es muy importante.
Prometeme。
Prometeme.
答应我。
Promise me.
(他咳嗽)
[HE COUGHS]
Prometeme。
Prometeme.
我保证。我会的。
I promise. I will.
(男人用西班牙语大喊)
[MEN SHOUT IN SPANISH]
好吧，看看我们能做些什么?
OK, let's see what we can do here, huh?
她叹了口气好了。
[SHE SIGHS] OK.
[她说西班牙语]-[他呻吟]
[SHE SPEAKS SPANISH] - [HE GROANS]
我们正在跟进。
We are followed.
被跟踪吗?由谁?
Being followed? By who?
男人。
Men.
坏男人。
Bad men.
Sicarios。
Sicarios.
好吧，让我看看这个。
OK, let me take a look at this.
[她叹息]-[他呻吟]
[SHE SIGHS] - [HE GROANS]
(她叹了口气)他在流血。
[SHE SIGHS] He's bleeding out.
他的血。琳达!
He's bleeding out. Linda!
[他咳嗽]-哇，哇，哇。嘘。
[HE COUGHS] - Whoa, whoa, whoa. Shh.
没关系。艾米莉亚，帮我让他冷静下来，亲爱的。
It's OK. Amelia, help me calm him down, sweetheart.
[他穿裤子]-[泰勒]:没关系。没关系。
[HE PANTS] - [TAYLOR]: It's OK. It's OK.
没关系。
It's OK.
(门摇铃)
[DOOR RATTLES]
那是什么?
[TAYLOR]: What was that?
我希望那不是树枝穿窗而过。
I hope that wasn't a branch going through a window.
琳达!
Linda!
(声巨响)
[LOUD BANG]
那不是树枝。
That was no branch.
阿米莉亚，帮我个忙。
Amelia, I want you to do me a favour here.
把手给我。
Give me your hands.
我要你用力压住那里，好吗?
I want you to put a lot of pressure on there, OK?
比你认为的要多。
More than you think you should.
我会尽快回来的。
I'm gonna be back as soon as I can.
好吧，我走后把门锁上
OK, lock this door behind me
然后再压回去，好吗?
and then put the pressure back on, OK?
(他轻轻地呻吟)
[HE GROANS SOFTLY]
爸爸。——(他伎俩)
Papa. - [HE WHEEZES]
爸爸。
Papa.
呆在这里。
Stay right there.
好的。-[男]:你是这里的负责人吗?
OK. - [MAN]: You in charge here?
是的。
Yes.
这里有一个男人和一个小女孩吗?
There a man and a little girl here?
[她喘着气抽泣]
[SHE GASPS AND SOBS]
一个男人和一个小女孩在这里?——(她尖叫)
A man and a little girl here? - [SHE SCREAMS]
嗯?
Huh?
(他会说西班牙语)
[HE SPEAKS SPANISH]
跟你说了我们要袭击他们。
Told you we hit them.
我要问你-不!
I'm gonna ask you-- - No!
最后一次。——(玫瑰呜咽)
One last time. - [ROSE WHIMPERS]
有没有一个男人…——(玫瑰抽泣)
Is there a man... - [ROSE SOBS]
…这里有个小女孩吗?
...and a little girl here?
你有两秒钟!——(她尖叫)
You have two seconds! - [SHE SHRIEKS]
好的!拜托!拜托!
OK! Please! Please!
好的。好的，跟我来。
OK. OK, come with me.
[她啜泣]-走路。
[SHE SOBS] - Walk.
走了!——好!好的!
Walk! - OK! OK!
嘿!
Hey!
快点。——好的。
Hurry up. - OK.
移动。——好的。
Move. - OK.
得更快。
Faster.
嘿,嘿…(他会说西班牙语)
Hey, hey... [HE SPEAKS SPANISH]
(他们说西班牙语)
[THEY SPEAK SPANISH]
嘿,嘿,看。——(叹了口气)
Hey, hey, look. - [SHE SIGHS]
我要的是那个男人和那个女孩，不是你。
I want the man and the girl, not you.
没关系。
It's OK.
好的。——走路。
OK. - Walk.
嘿,嘿,嘿!
Hey, hey, hey!
在这里是什么?
What's in here?
只是个客房而已。——嘘!
It's just a guest room. - Shh!
他们是武装吗?
Are they armed?
我不知道。
I don't know.
(他咕哝声)
[HE GRUNTS]
[男子]:他们在哪里?
[MAN]: Where are they?
我不知道。-他们在里面吗?
I don't know. - Were they in there?
他们是。-是的，他们是。是的。
Were they-- - Yes, they were. Yes.
(遥远的嘎吱嘎吱声)
[DISTANT CREAK]
嘘。
Shh.
和我呆在一起。来吧。
Stay with me. Come on.
在那里是什么?
What's in there?
什么都没有。这只是个洗衣房。
Nothing. It's just a laundry room.
去敲门，告诉他们是你。让他们敞开心扉。
Knock on the door and tell them it's you. Tell them to open up.
(叹了口气)
[SHE SIGHS]
你好,是我。
Hello, it's me.
你能把门打开吗?
Can you open the door?
离开!
Move away!
(旧金山咳嗽)
[FRANCISCO COUGHS]
(他咳嗽)
[HE COUGHS]
(男):哦,pobrecito。
[MAN]: Ay, pobrecito.
你看起来不太好，派莎。
You don't look good, Paisa.
让我们快点。
Let's do this quick.
代码在哪里?
Where's the code?
是在芯片上吗?闪存驱动器吗?什么东西吗?
Is it on a chip or something? Flash drive? Something?
嘿。
Hey.
(他咳嗽)-嘿，嘿，嘿。
[HE COUGHS] - Hey, hey, hey.
醒来。
Wake up.
(他说西班牙语)在哪里?
[HE SPEAKS SPANISH] Where is it?
嘿,嘿,嘿!看。看着我。看!
Hey, hey, hey! Look. Look at me. Look!
它是……是在这里吗?嗯?
Is it... Is it in here? Huh?
嘿,嘿。Digame。告诉我，它在哪里?
Hey, hey. Dígame. Tell me, where is it?
不然我就像对你哥哥那样对你。
Or I'll do to you what I did to your brother.
Digame。Digame,嗯?
Dígame. Dígame, eh?
(他会说西班牙语)
[HE SPEAKS SPANISH]
你觉得你可以抛弃我们吗?
You think you could turn your back on us, huh?
你认为这些美国人
You think these Americans
比我更能保护你吗?
are gonna protect you more than me?
嘿,嘿。
Hey, hey.
嘿，看，看，看…
Hey, look, look, look...
我不在乎你妻子是否出庭作证。
I don't care if your wife testifies.
我也不在乎
I don't care.
那是我叔叔的事。嗯?
That's my uncle's business. Hmm?
他派我们来杀你，别想他了。
He sent us here to take you out, but forget him.
他不像我那么体贴。
He's not as considerate as I am.
看，看，看，看……
Look, look, look, look...
你把密码给我，我们就分开。
You give me the code, we split it.
(他会说西班牙语)
[HE SPEAKS SPANISH]
我们做自己的事。嗯?
We do our own thing. Hmm?
你要多少我就给你多少。
I'll give you as much as you want.
你，你的家人，你走路。
You, your family, you walk.
你把密码给我，我们就有钱了。
Hey, you give me that code and we're rich.
我们很有钱，伙计。
We're very rich, my man.
(他轻笑)嘿，嘿……
[HE CHUCKLES] Hey, hey...
我只需要那个密码。
I just need that code.
你……你有吗?
You... You have it?
你……你女儿有吗?
You... Your daughter has it?
(他吐)
[HE SPITS]
(他会说西班牙语)
[HE SPEAKS SPANISH]
(FRANCISCO呻吟)
[FRANCISCO GROANS]
你觉得你能背叛我吗?
Think you can turn your back on me?
嘿，嘿，嘿!——(FRANCISCO呻吟)
[TAYLOR]: Hey, hey, hey! - [FRANCISCO GROANS]
请停止。
Please, stop.
请。他需要治疗
Please. He needs medical attention.
你知道什么?
What do you know?
我什么都不知道，我发誓。
I don't know anything, I swear.
他们给你的?-他们什么都没给我
They gave it to you? - They didn't give me anything.
我发誓。
I swear.
嘿,嘿,嘿!钱在哪里?
Hey, hey, hey! Where's the money?
钱在哪里?——(他呻吟)
Where's the money? - [HE GROANS]
告诉我，钱在哪里?钱呢?
Tell me, where's the money? Where's the money, huh?
钱在哪里?——(他呻吟)
Where's the money? - [HE GROANS]
嘿!嘿!
Hey! Hey!
嘿,嘿。
Hey, hey.
嗨,wh…钱在哪里?
Hey, wh... where's the money?
嘿，钱在哪儿?
Hey, where's the money?
女孩在哪里?
Where's the girl?
我不…我不知道。
I don't... I don't know.
等等!等待。——什么?
Wait! Wait. - What?
等待。你想要个优盘什么的，对吧?
Wait. You want a flash drive or something, right?
如果是这样，我…我有一个地方——
If it's that, I... I have a place--
走路。走了!——好的。
Walk. Walk! - OK.
好吧……(她喘息声)
OK... [SHE GASPS]
[倾盆大雨]-[雷声轰鸣]
[RAIN POURS] - [THUNDER RUMBLES]
这是什么?
What's this?
嗯…
Um...
插进去就可以了。插进去就可以了。
Plug it in. Plug it in.
一步走了。
Step away.
(雷声隆隆地)
[THUNDER RUMBLES]
(风的咆哮)
[WIND HOWLS]
什么?
What?
我饿了。
I'm hungry.
(她抽泣)
[SHE SOBS]
(叹了口气)
[SHE SIGHS]
(门咯吱声,悄悄地)
[DOOR CREAKS QUIETLY]
(点击他的舌头)
[HE CLICKS TONGUE]
(他叹了口气)
[HE SIGHS]
(阿梅利亚轻声呜咽)
[AMELIA WHIMPERS SOFTLY]
(她的裤子)
[SHE PANTS]
最近生意不太好。
Uh, business hasn't been so great lately.
是吗?
Yeah?
你觉得你在这个豪宅里很难受吗?
You think you have it bad here in this big fancy mansion?
不是你看到的那样。
It's not what it looks like.
我从父亲那里继承了这个地方。
I inherited this place from my father.
(男):你不知道。
[MAN]: You have no idea.
你爸爸的宗教吗?
Your dad religious?
他创办这个地方是为了教会
He started this place as a church ministry
作为……的方法。回馈给人们…
as a way to... give back to people that...
一生都在帮助别人。
had spent their lives helping other people.
是的,他是。
Yeah, he was.
我也是……
So was I...
然后,事情发生了。
then things happened.
(键盘水龙头)
[KEYBOARD TAPS]
(风的咆哮)
[WIND HOWLS]
(阿米莉亚叹了口气)
[AMELIA SIGHS]
你投资过加密货币吗?
You ever invest in cryptocurrency?
你应该。
You should.
看到……
See...
我也在做家族生意。
I'm in a family business, too.
你做你该做的。
You do what you gotta do.
我也一样。
So do I.
(键盘瓣)
[KEYBOARD CLACKS]
(打雷)
[THUNDER CRASHES]
那是哪儿?
Where is that?
这些都是老了。我们甚至不用它们
These are old. We don't even use them--
(她呻吟)——玩够了游戏!
[SHE GROANS] - Enough with the games already!
现在就带我去。走了!
Take me there now. Walk!
(风吹口哨)
[WIND WHISTLES]
地板(吱吱的响声)
[FLOORBOARD CREAKS]
(风的咆哮)
[WIND HOWLS]
[人]:移动。
[MAN]: Move.
动!
Move!
(他用西班牙语大喊)
[HE SHOUTS IN SPANISH]
阿米莉亚,快跑!
Amelia, run!
(他小声说):嘿，没有枪。没有枪!
[HE WHISPERS]: Hey, no gun. No gun!
(她的裤子)
[SHE PANTS]
(他咕哝声)
[HE GRUNTS]
[人]:Chachita……
[MAN]: Chachita...
Chachita吗?
Chachita?
(他会说西班牙语)
[HE SPEAKS SPANISH]
Chachita吗?
Chachita?
(他会说西班牙语)
[HE SPEAKS SPANISH]
[他说西班牙语]-[门吱吱作响]
[HE SPEAKS SPANISH] - [DOOR CREAKS]
(男):嘘。
[MAN]: Psst.
(举起丁氏)
[LIFT DINGS]
(门吱吱的响声轻声)
[DOOR CREAKS SOFTLY]
(电梯门关闭)
[LIFT DOORS SHUT]
他们哪儿也不会去
They're not going anywhere
在这样的风暴下不行。
not with this storm.
让我们等待。
Let's just wait.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
科摩吗?-你在干什么?
Como? - What are you doing?
这地方大约有100个房间。你要一遍一遍吗?
This place got about 100 rooms. You wanna go through 'em all?
那个女孩。
The girl.
古兹曼派我们来结束这一切。(他会说西班牙语)
Guzman sent us to end this. [HE SPEAKS SPANISH]
嘘。
Shh.
别担心我叔叔。(我们按我的方式做。)
Don't worry about my uncle. We're doing it my way.
噢,是吗?
Oh, yeah?
是的。
Yeah.
好的。
OK.
他们会来找我们的。
They'll come to us.
(轻点击)
[LIGHTER CLICKS]
(他呼出)
[HE EXHALES]
(叹了口气)
[SHE SIGHS]
(打雷)
[THUNDER CRASHES]
(门咯吱声)
[DOOR CREAKS]
(举起丁氏)
[LIFT DINGS]
你们也该邀请我们去你们的俱乐部了。
About time you guys invited us girls to your club.
今天我们破例一次。
We'll make an exception today.
每个人都可以吗?
Is everyone OK?
(玫瑰抽噎)
[ROSE SNIFFLES]
嗯…
Mmm...
可怜的琳达。
Poor Linda.
我简直不敢相信。
I just can't believe it.
可怜的,可怜的琳达。
Poor, poor Linda.
她从没对任何人做过坏事。
She ain't never done nothing wrong to nobody.
没有人!
Nobody!
(玫瑰抽噎)
[ROSE SNIFFLES]
我们不能就这么呆在这里。
[COLONEL]: W-we can't just stay down here.
(我们得想出一个计划。)
We need to come up with a plan.
嗯哼。
Mm-hmm.
噢,是吗?
Oh, yeah?
谁任命你当船长的?
Who made you captain of the ship?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry
但我们要去哪儿呢?
but where are we gonna go, huh?
我们不能把泰勒一个人留在上面。
We can't just leave Taylor alone up there.
我就是这个意思。
T-that's what I'm saying.
你要带我们上战场吗，假上校先生?
You gonna lead us into battle, Mr Fake Colonel?
【柔丝】你能不能别理他?
[ROSE]: Will you leave him alone?
你怎么了?
What is your problem?
(他表现得好像他是老板。
He acts like he's the boss
他和我们没什么不同。
when he's no different than the rest of us.
这不是正确的吗?
Isn't that right?
告诉他们…“上校”!
Tell 'em... "Colonel"!
你怎么了?
What is wrong with you?
现在不是说…的时候
This is hardly the time to--
不,他是对的。
No, he's right.
他是对的。我不是上校，如果你一定要知道的话。
He's right. I'm not a colonel, if you must know.
我当过兵……
I was in the Army...
但当我的部队出兵时，我不能去。
but when my battalion shipped out, I couldn't go.
结果发现我有脊椎问题。
Turned out I had a spinal condition.
他们说不适合服役。
Unfit to serve, they said.
所以，我花了整个韩国事件
So, I spent the whole Korean affair
在办公桌后面的办公室里。
in an office behind a desk.
没开过一枪。
Never fired a shot.
不过，我确实是一步步爬上来的。
Though, I did rise up through the ranks.
这很容易，当所有的男人…
It was easy, when all the men...
所有真正的男人都走了。
all the real men were gone.
我是一名少校。
I was a major.
我已经被提升为中校了
I was set for promotion to lieutenant colonel
然后我们营的大部分人都回来了。
and then my battalion came back, most of them.
他们说
And they said
“弗雷泽…你要当中校了?”
"Fraser... you're gonna be a lieutenant colonel?"
(他轻笑)我们对此大笑了一场
[HE CHUCKLES] We had a good laugh about it
他们又敬了礼又笑。
and they saluted and laughed.
所以，当升职的时候……
So, when it came time for the promotion...
我否认了。
I denied it.
只是说，“没关系。”
Just said, "never mind."
所以,你是对的…
So, you're right...
我不是上校
I'm not a colonel
连中校都不是。
not even a lieutenant colonel.
我什么都不知道，也没有什么特殊资格
I don't know any more or have any special qualifications
比这里的任何人都更能帮我们摆脱困境。
to get us out of this mess than anyone else here.
所以…
So...
(他咂咂嘴)就在那儿。
[HE SMACKS LIPS] There it is.
哦,谁在乎呢?
Oh, who cares?
我丈夫在朝鲜战争中赚了一大笔钱
My husband spent the Korean War making a fortune
偷偷啤酒规定
sneaking beer provisions
然后在另一边卖。
and then selling them on the side.
听着，我们都不是英雄。
Listen, ain't none of us heroes.
我们现在要做的是我想知道的。
What we gonna do now is what I wanna know.
(IDA杂音)
[IDA MURMURS]
(玫瑰):艾达?
[ROSE]: Ida?
我…-[艾达]:握住我的手。
I... - [IDA]: Hold my hand.
就是这样。来吧。
That's it. Come on.
来吧。
Come on.
哦,天父…
Oh, Heavenly Father...
我们现在就来找你。
we come to you now.
我们需要你。
We need you.
(玫瑰):是的,主。
[ROSE]: Yes, Lord.
这是她的长诗吗?
Is this gonna be one of her long ones?
请照看好这个女孩……
Please watch over the girl...
那个小女孩，爸爸。
the little girl, Father.
保证她的安全。——(玫瑰):嗯。
Keep her safe. - [ROSE]: Mm-hmm.
【艾达】:保护她免受恶魔的伤害。
[IDA]: Protect her from this evil.
让她安全……
Keep her safe...
在你翅膀的阴影下。
under the shadow of your wing.
(罗丝):感谢主。
[ROSE]: Thank you, Lord.
【艾达】:主啊，现在我们把泰勒抬到你面前。
[IDA]: And we lift up Taylor to you now, Lord.
(玫瑰):是的。
[ROSE]: Yes.
[艾达]:我们祈祷她现在转向你。
[IDA]: We pray that she turns to you now.
(门咯吱声)
[DOOR CREAKS]
(叹了口气)
[SHE SIGHS]
[艾达]:她的负担很重
[IDA]: Her burden is heavy
但是你们的负担是轻的。
but your burden is light.
保证我们在这场风暴中的安全。
And keep us all safe in this storm.
(声音变了):我们知道审判会发生……
[VOICE BREAKS]: We know that trials happen...
但你更伟大。
but You are greater.
(她抽泣)
[SHE SOBS]
(叹了口气)
[SHE SIGHS]
【艾达】:帮助我们所有人完全信任你。
[IDA]: Help us all to trust in You entirely.
我们以你的名义祈祷。——(泰勒抽泣)
In Your name, we pray. - [TAYLOR SOBS]
[艾达]:尊重他的名字。——(叹了口气)
[IDA]: Honour His name. - [SHE SIGHS]
(门)
[DOOR OPENS]
亲爱的，是我。
Oh, sweetie, it's just me.
没关系。我不会伤害你的。
It's OK. I'm not gonna hurt you.
你可以相信我。没关系。没关系。
You can trust me. It's OK. It's OK.
没关系。嘘。
It's OK. Shh.
嘘。没关系。——(阿米莉亚喘息声)
Shh. It's OK. - [AMELIA GASPS]
没关系。
It's OK.
没关系。没关系。
It's OK. It's OK.
这些人，他们在找什么。
These men, they're looking for something.
某种密码之类的。你知道是什么吗?
Some kind of code or something. Do you know what it is?
不。
No.
如果我们找到并交给他们，他们就会消失。
If we find it and give it to them, they'll go away.
你确定吗?
Are you sure?
我不知道。
I don't know.
好的。
OK.
我们得离开这里。
We've gotta get outta here.
如果我能让你离开这房子
If I can get you out of this house
你觉得你能跑到附近的邻居那里吗
do you think you can run to one of the nearby neighbours
然后想办法帮我们?
and get us help somehow?
[树咯吱作响]-[风呼啸]
[TREES CREAK] - [WIND HOWLS]
(她叹了口气)好吧，不安全。
[SHE SIGHS] OK, it's not safe.
我们最好给你找个安全的地方。我们走吧。来吧。
We better find somewhere safe for you. Let's go. Come on.
(门轻声尖叫)
[DOOR SQUEAKS SOFTLY]
好吧……
Alright...
在我的信号……我们运行。
On my signal... we run.
三个……两个……一个。
Three... two... one.
(举起丁氏)
[LIFT DINGS]
(遥远的咔嗒声)
[DISTANT CLATTER]
(她低声说):他下去，我们上去。
[SHE WHISPERS]: He goes down, we go up.
你住在这里吗?
You live here?
你富有。
You're rich.
就像这样。相信我。
It just looks like that. Trust me.
(她低声说):这边走。
[SHE WHISPERS]: This way.
来吧。
Come on.
(阿米莉亚):哦,哇。
[AMELIA]: Oh, wow.
(雷声隆隆地)
[THUNDER RUMBLES]
(泰勒):在这里。穿过这里。
[TAYLOR]: Right here. Right through here.
你一定有一个大家庭。
You must have a big family.
有时候确实是这样的。
It sure feels like it sometimes.
他们在哪儿?
Where are they?
哦，别担心他们。他们非常足智多谋。
Oh, don't worry about them. They're pretty resourceful.
他们会在这附近的某个地方。
They'll be around here somewhere.
来吧。穿过这里。
Come on. Right through here.
这边走，亲爱的。
Right this way, sweetie.
她叹了口气好了。
[SHE SIGHS] OK.
好了,不要判断。
Alright, don't judge.
没关系。我的房间也很乱。
It's OK. My room's messy, too.
好的。
OK.
哇。
Wow.
我很久没来过这里了。
I haven't been in here in a long time.
这是你干的?
You did this?
不是最近,但是……是的，我像你这么大的时候。
Not recently, but... yeah, when I was about your age.
(她叹了口气)哦，我差点忘了。
[SHE SIGHS] Well, I almost forgot.
[阿米莉亚]那是什么?
[AMELIA]: What is that?
嗯,这是……
Well, it's...
我把重要的东西妥善保管的地方。
a place where I keep important things for safekeeping.
(她笑)
[SHE CHUCKLES]
[阿米莉亚]那是谁?
[AMELIA]: Who is that?
那就是我。——这是你吗?
That's me. - That's you?
这是我的父母还和我们在一起的时候。
[TAYLOR]: That's my mum and dad when they were still with us.
这是开业那天拍的。
This was taken on the day they opened this place.
他们想为穷人开一个地方
They wanted to open a place for poor people
这样等他们长大了，就有地方住了。
so that when they got older, they had a place to live.
(她温柔地笑)
[SHE CHUCKLES SOFTLY]
[阿米莉亚]:那些人都是谁?
[AMELIA]: Who are all those people?
这些人来自教堂。
These were people from the church.
人们献出了自己的时间…
People that donated their time and...
还有他们的钱，这样我们才能开业。
and their money so that we could open.
我记得这一天。
I remember this day.
他们都在教堂的入口处
They were all in the entrance of the church
他们做了很长的祈祷…
and they were saying this really long prayer and...
我满脑子想的都是"我们什么时候吃饭"
all I could think about was, "When are we gonna eat?"
(她笑)
[SHE CHUCKLES]
看看那些笑容。
Look at those smiles.
我有段时间没看到了。
I haven't seen that in a while.
艾米莉亚，我得去看看…
Amelia, I have to go and check on...
[阿米莉亚]:这是什么?
[AMELIA]: What is this?
那是我最好的朋友给我的最喜欢的贝壳。
That was my favourite shell that my best friend gave me.
[阿米莉亚]:你有兄弟姐妹吗?
[AMELIA]: Do you have a brother or a sister?
你呢?
Do you?
不了。
Not anymore.
我有个妹妹……一个大姐姐。
I had a sister... a big sister.
我很抱歉。
I'm sorry.
没关系。
It's OK.
我几乎不记得。
I hardly remember.
我小的时候。
I was little.
是卡特尔干的。
It was the cartel.
你有孩子吗?
Do you have kids?
不。
No.
哦。
Oh.
我想，但我做不到。
I wanted to, but I couldn't.
对不起。
Sorry.
我想这不是命中注定的。
It wasn't meant to be, I guess.
有时候我们要相信上帝有不同的计划。
Sometimes we just have to trust God has a different plan.
(雷声隆隆地)
[THUNDER RUMBLES]
(打雷)
[THUNDER CRASHES]
(叹了口气)
[SHE SIGHS]
我得下楼了。
I need to go downstairs.
我得去看看我的朋友们，确保他们没事。
I need to check on my friends and make sure they're OK.
好的。
OK.
但我希望你留在这里。你在这里会很安全。
I want you to stay here, though. You'll be safe here.
好的。
OK.
我会的。
I will.
(她会说西班牙语)
[SHE SPEAKS SPANISH]
这是什么意思?
What does that mean?
摆脱他们。
Get rid of them.
(打雷)
[THUNDER CRASHES]
(他咕哝声)
[HE GRUNTS]
(除纤颤器开始震动)
[DEFIBRILLATOR WHIRS]
[啪]-[他呻吟]
[SNAP] - [HE GROANS]
(雷声裂缝)
[THUNDER CRACKS]
(风的咆哮)
[WIND HOWLS]
(发电机当啷声)
[GENERATOR CLANKS]
泰勒?
Taylor?
喂?
Hello?
(风的咆哮)
[WIND HOWLS]
[发电机发出叮当声和嗡嗡声]
[GENERATOR CLANKS AND WHIRS]
(男):嘿!来这里!
[MAN]: Hey! Come here!
来这里!来这里!来这里!
Come here! Come here! Come here!
来吧。来吧!
Come on. Come on!
[泰勒尖叫]-[他咕哝着]
[TAYLOR SCREECHES] - [HE GRUNTS]
(他们嘀咕着)
[THEY GRUNT]
(泰勒尖叫)
[TAYLOR SHRIEKS]
(她呻吟)
[SHE GROANS]
[他咕哝着]-[她尖叫着]
[HE GRUNTS] - [SHE SHRIEKS]
(她大叫)
[SHE YELLS]
(他哭泣)
[HE WAILS]
(他们嘀咕着)
[THEY GRUNT]
够了!
Enough!
(枪声)
[GUNSHOTS]
(风的咆哮)
[WIND HOWLS]
(他会说西班牙语)
[HE SPEAKS SPANISH]
(他们说西班牙语)
[THEY SPEAK SPANISH]
按我说的做。
We do it my way.
我们等待。
We wait.
(打雷)
[THUNDER CRASHES]
(他深深地叹息)
[HE SIGHS DEEPLY]
所以…
So...
没人知道，是吧?
No one knows anything, huh?
你拿了我的东西。
You have something that belongs to me.
你把它给我然后我们…
You give it to me and we...
我们走。
we go.
我跟你说了，我们不知道你在找什么。
Look, I told you, we don't know what you're looking for.
好吗?我们跟这事一点关系都没有。
OK? We don't have anything to do with this.
(她哭)
[SHE CRIES]
(他用西班牙语喃喃自语)
[HE MUTTERS IN SPANISH]
(泰勒):不!-[他说西班牙语]
[TAYLOR]: No! - [HE SPEAKS SPANISH]
坐下来!你会告诉我的。
Sit down! You will tell me.
告诉我在哪儿!
Tell me where it is!
我不知道。我不知道那是什么。
I don't know. I don't know what it is.
你爸爸的密码。在哪里?在哪里?
The code from your papa. Where is it? Where is it?
这就够了。
That's enough.
你必须知道!你告诉我!
You have to know! You tell me!
没有se !没有，拜托!
No se! No se, por favor!
够了!
That's enough!
没有人。
None of us.
听我的。
Listen to me.
我想和你谈谈。
I wanna talk to you.
别客气。
Tu y tu muchachos.
米拉,米拉!
Mira, mira!
你在这里做得够多了。
You have done enough here.
你做得够多了!
You have done enough!
你和你的人离开这里
You and your men will leave this place
再也不回来了。
and never come back again.
这是个好地方……
This is a good place...
一个安全的地方。
a safe place.
你不知道这些，所以我要告诉你。
You don't know this, so I am going to tell you.
她父亲开这个家的时候
When her father opened this home
他用一首诗来献给他
he dedicated it with a verse
圣经，以赛亚书25:4。
a Bible verse, Isaiah 25:4.
“这是穷人在苦难中的避难所……
"A refuge for the needy in their distress...
一个躲避暴风雨的避难所……”
a shelter from the storm..."
一个躲避暴风雨的地方!
A shelter from the storm!
这是完美的!
That is perfect!
尤其是今天。
Especially for today.
你知道以赛亚书25章还说了什么吗?
Do you know what else Isaiah 25 said?
那日他们必起来说
"In that day they will rise up and they will say
他真是我们的神。
'Surely He is our God.
我们信任他……他救了我们。’”
We trusted in Him... and He saved us.'"
他救了我们!
He saved us!
所以,你……
So, you...
可以威胁我们…
can threaten us...
你可以伤害我们
you can hurt us
但你不能摧毁我们…
but you cannot destroy us...
因为我们是安全的。
because we are safe.
不在这房子里……
Not in this house...
我们在祂里面是安全的。
we are safe in Him.
他是我们的堡垒。
He is our fortress.
现在，滚出去!
And now, get out!
你不安全!——(她低声呻吟)
You're not safe! - [SHE WHIMPERS]
你怎么敢?
How dare you?
你以为你是谁啊?
Who do you think you are?
她已经93岁了。
She's a 93-year-old woman.
九十三年的历史
Ninety-three years old
她的小手指更有勇气
and she has more courage in her little finger
比你拥有的更多
than you will ever have.
你是个胆小鬼!
You are a coward!
懦夫。
A coward.
[人]:闭嘴。
[MAN]: Shut up.
(枪)
[GUNSHOT]
走吧!走吧!
Go! Go!
动!
Move!
(枪声)
[GUNSHOTS]
[枪声]-帮我一下。
[GUNSHOTS] - Help me with this.
推动!——(枪声)
Push! - [GUNSHOTS]
(泰勒咕哝声)
[TAYLOR GRUNTS]
(FRASER):推!推动!——(泰勒咕哝声)
[FRASER]: Push! Push! - [TAYLOR GRUNTS]
(它们哼了一声)——趴下!
[THEY GRUNT] - Stay down!
(枪声)
[GUNSHOTS]
不…——(枪旋塞)
No... - [GUN COCKS]
(枪声)
[GUNSHOTS]
(枪点击)
[GUN CLICKS]
(打雷)
[THUNDER CRASHES]
(枪声)
[GUNSHOTS]
你在干什么?你会害死我们的!
What are you doing? You're gonna get us killed!
(枪声)
[GUNSHOTS]
[子弹反弹]-[他呻吟]
[BULLET RICOCHETS] - [HE GROANS]
[他大叫]-[枪声]
[HE YELLS] - [GUNSHOTS]
(枪)
[GUNSHOT]
(雷声裂缝)
[THUNDER CRACKS]
(雨倒)
[RAIN POURS]
里面什么都没有了。
[COLE]: It's all clear in there.
每个人都好吗?
Everybody OK?
她好了吗?
Is she alright?
不，她需要帮助。我马上回来。
No, she needs help. I'll be right back.
还有其他坏人吗?-[弗雷泽]:你还好吧?
Any other bad guys? - [FRASER]: You alright?
不，只有三个。
No, just the three.
你的爸爸在哪里?
Where's your dad?
在你爸爸吗?
Donde tu papa?
我很抱歉。
I'm sorry.
你没事吧?
Are you gonna be OK?
你确定吗?
You sure?
(安静地):我得问你点事。
[QUIETLY]: I have to ask you something.
(他叹了口气)密码在哪里……
[HE SIGHS] Where's the code...
你爸爸和他一起的吗?
that your dad had with him?
你不知道?
You don't know?
我知道你现在很难过，好吗?
I know it's difficult right now, OK?
但我需要你为我好好想想。
But I need you to think real hard for me.
我不知道。
I don't know.
你确定不知道在哪儿吗?
You sure you don't know where it is?
这很重要。
It's very important.
好的。
OK.
没有问题。
No problem.
听好了,每一个人。
Listen up, everyone.
你能不能听我说几句。
If I can just get your attention for a minute.
我是缉毒局的科尔·贝内特。
I'm Cole Bennett with the DEA.
有一个重要的证据
There's an important piece of evidence
这位年轻的女士和她的父亲在运输
this young lady and her father were transporting
作为调查的一部分
as part of an investigation.
没有它……
Without it...
一些非常坏的人会被释放。
some very bad men will go free.
它是什么?它看起来像什么?
What is it? What does it look like?
不完全确定。
Not exactly sure.
这是电脑驱动器上的代码，某种芯片。
It's a code on a computer drive, a chip of some kind.
你们有人见过这样的东西吗?
Have any of you seen anything like that?
(玫瑰):没有。——(ARTHUR):没有。
[ROSE]: No. - [ARTHUR]: No.
你确定吗?
Are you sure?
[FONZY]:我们确定。
[FONZY]: We're sure.
我能再问你一遍吗?
Can I ask you again?
我要你好好想想，亲爱的。
I want you to think, honey.
回想一下你和你爸爸刚来的时候。
Think back when you first got here with your dad.
我不知道。
I don't know.
我不记得了。
I cannot remember.
来吧。
Come on.
的想法!
Think!
这是怎么呢
What's going on?
(雷声隆隆地)
[THUNDER RUMBLES]
让我猜猜……(叹了口气)
Let me guess... [SHE SIGHS]
你在找密码。
You're looking for a code.
你知道它在哪儿吗?
Do you know where it is?
我对你的生意一无所知。
I don't know anything about your business.
没有人知道。
None of us do.
你们那里的人……所做的事。
One of you... does.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
听我的。
Listen to me.
告诉我密码在哪里。
Tell me where the code is.
在哪里?
Where is it?
你父亲有个包…一个黑色的袋子里。
Your father had a bag... a black bag.
在哪里?说出来!
Where is it? Speak up!
在哪里?
Where is it?
啊…
Ah...
突然之间，你就知道了。
All of a sudden, you know things.
让她走了。
Let her go.
(她咕哝声)
[SHE GRUNTS]
(她呻吟)
[SHE GROANS]
你们都呆在这儿。
All of you stay here.
你明白吗?
Do you understand?
呆在这儿!
Stay here!
(FRASER):理解。
[FRASER]: Understood.
[她呻吟]- [FONZY]:哦，我的上帝。
[SHE GROANS] - [FONZY]: Oh, my God.
你还好吗?——(她的裤子)
Are you OK? - [SHE PANTS]
(监控哔哔声)
[MONITOR BEEPS]
泰勒小姐吗?
Miss Taylor?
来吧。
Come on.
好了，听我说。
Alright, stay with me.
[国际开发协会]:这个女孩……她是好吗?
[IDA]: The girl... she's OK?
没关系。没关系。坚持下去..
That's OK. It's OK. Hang in there.
坚持下去..我得到了你。
Hang in there. I got you.
我有。-听着。
I got-- - Listen.
(IDA喘息声)
[IDA GASPS]
信任……
Trust...
(她喘息声)
[SHE GASPS]
他。
Him.
[她喘着气]-[监视器哔哔声]
[SHE GASPS] - [MONITOR BEEPS]
(监控持平)
[MONITOR FLATLINES]
(她抽泣)不…
[SHE SOBS] No...
(她喊道)不，不!
[SHE CRIES] No, no!
(她抽泣)
[SHE SOBS]
不…
No...
我…
I...
(她尖叫)我不能!哦……
[SHE SHRIEKS] I can't! Oh...
我不能，我不能。哦!
I can't, I can't. Oh!
我再也受不了了。我不能这么做……
I can't do this anymore. I can't do this any...
(玫瑰):泰勒小姐。
[ROSE]: Miss Taylor.
[FONZY]:嘿。-我不能…我…
[FONZY]: Hey. - I can't... I...
现在来吧。
Come on now.
振作起来。
Snap out of it.
(她抽泣)
[SHE SOBS]
(FONZY):会没事的。
[FONZY]: It's gonna be OK.
艾达会这么说。
Ida would say that.
这是正确的。
That's right.
一步一步来。
One step at a time.
她会这么说。
That's what she'd say.
相信下一步。
Trust the next step.
(她深深呼吸)
[SHE BREATHES DEEPLY]
(FONZY普通员工)
[FONZY GRUNTS]
(叹了口气)
[SHE SIGHS]
(钟)
[CLOCK TICKS]
嘿…
Hey...
你听到了吗?
You hear that?
嗯?
Hmm?
完全正确。
Exactly.
我也不。
Me neither.
[亚瑟]:一定是风暴中心。
[ARTHUR]: Must be the eye of the storm.
(泰勒叹了口气)
[TAYLOR SIGHS]
你知道的…我想我喜欢这个样子。
You know... I think I like that look.
你要去哪里?
Where you going?
我要采取下一步行动。
I'm gonna take that next step.
(叹了口气)
[SHE SIGHS]
这种方式吗?
This way?
来吧，我们继续找。
Come on, let's keep looking.
(他咕哝声)
[HE GRUNTS]
(她尖叫)不!
[SHE SCREAMS] No!
加油,阿米莉亚!走吧!走吧!
Come on, Amelia! Go! Go!
好吧，让我想想。躲起来。隐藏在这里。隐藏在这里。
Alright, let me think. Hide. Hide here. Hide here.
[倾盆大雨]-[她穿裤子]
[RAIN POURS] - [SHE PANTS]
好吧……
OK...
你知道你在干什么吗?
What do you think you're doing, huh?
你知道它在哪儿。
You know where it is.
[枪声]-[他呻吟]
[GUNSHOT] - [HE GROANS]
你想把那笔钱留给自己。
You want to keep that money for yourself.
它是我的。
It's mine.
你知道我在这上面花了多少年吗?
You know how many years I put into this?
肮脏的地方行政区域的贫民窟。
Filthy barrio slums.
[枪声]-[他呻吟]
[GUNSHOT] - [HE GROANS]
肮脏的贫民窟的老鼠……
Filthy slum rats...
把毒品带进来。
bringing drugs in here.
你到底站在哪一边?
Whose side are you on?
他们在杀我的人。
They're killing my men.
我们的男人。
Our men.
叛徒……
That traitor...
他女儿也在其中。
and his daughter are in the middle of it.
她的母亲也是。
So was her mother.
我也要除掉那个小矮子……
And I will get rid of that little runt, too...
如果她不告诉我我想知道的。
if she doesn't tell me what I wanna know.
[泰勒尖叫]-[他咕哝着]
[TAYLOR SCREAMS] - [HE GRUNTS]
(身体砰砰声)
[BODY THUDS]
(雷声隆隆地)
[THUNDER RUMBLES]
(她的裤子)
[SHE PANTS]
到这里来。
Come here.
[雨滴滴落]-[雷声隆隆]
[RAIN TRICKLES] - [THUNDER RUMBLES]
(泰勒抽泣)
[TAYLOR SOBS]
(他们呜咽)
[THEY SOB]
我很抱歉。
I'm so sorry.
我很抱歉……——这是T !T !
I'm so sorry... - It's T! It's T!
(他们哭)
[THEY CRY]
没关系。
It's OK.
[她抽泣]没事的。
[SHE SOBS] It's OK.
(玫瑰抽噎)
[ROSE SNIFFLES]
(他叹了口气)
[HE SIGHS]
(女):好的。
[WOMAN]: OK.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
原谅我。
Excuse me.
给你。——谢谢。
Here you go. - Thank you.
阿米莉亚，你知道这些文件是什么吗?
Amelia, do you know what these papers are?
一点。
A little bit.
沃德小姐正在申请寄养家庭。
Miss Ward is applying for foster care.
你知道那是什么吗?
Do you know what that is?
我想是的。
I think so.
意思是，如果你想…
It means that, if you want to...
你也许可以在这里住上一段时间。
you may be able to stay here for a while.
我可以和她在一起吗?
I can stay with her?
嗯，有一些事情要讨论，但是…
Well, there are a few things to go over, but...
我们也许能做到。
we might be able to make that happen.
哦，等一下。
Oh, just a sec.
我想我知道她可能去哪了。
I think I know where she might be going.
我们马上回来。
We'll be right back.
好的。
OK.
(泰勒):那是什么?
[TAYLOR]: What's that?
我父亲给我的。
My father gave it to me.
他说那是我母亲的。
He said it belonged to my mother.
它很漂亮。
It's very pretty.
他告诉我不要让任何人得到它
He told me not to let anyone have it
所以我就像你一样藏在这里。
so I hid it here, like you did.
我能看一下吗?
Can I see it for a second?
(并)
[SHE SCOFFS]
你父亲是对的。
Your father was right.
这是一条非常非常特别的项链。
This is a very, very special necklace.
一个我很亲近的人曾经告诉我
Someone I was very close to once told me
你所要做的就是信任。
that all you have to do is trust.
一个abuelita吗?
An abuelita?
是的。
Yeah.
即使你认为有些事是不可能的
That even when you think something's impossible
总会有办法的。
there is always, always a way.
我父亲对这地方的看法是对的。
My father was right about this place.
它非常特别。
It's very special.
喜欢我的项链吗?
Like my necklace?
是的…
Yeah...
喜欢你的项链。
like your necklace.
这是一份非常珍贵的礼物。
This is a very valuable gift.
一定要永远珍惜它。
Make sure you cherish it always.
哦，这是什么?
Ooh, what is this?
我好长时间没看到这个了。
Oh, wow, I haven't seen that in a long time.
你喜欢画画吗?
Do you like to draw?
(阿米莉亚):是的。——我也是。
[AMELIA]: Yeah. - Me too.
[阿米莉亚]:在家里，我的房间里有一堆照片。
[AMELIA]: At home I had a bunch of pictures in my room.
(泰勒):你做的?
[TAYLOR]: You did?
(继续喋喋不休朦胧地)
[CHATTER CONTINUES INDISTINCTLY]